<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>XMPP</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2016-02-08T22:25:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>The 19th XMPP Summit and FOSDEM 2016</title><link href="/2016/02/the-19th-xmpp-summit-and-fosdem-2016" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-08T22:25:00+01:00</published><author><name>Tobi</name></author><id>tag:,2016-02-08:2016/02/the-19th-xmpp-summit-and-fosdem-2016</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;19th XMPP Summit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late January 2016, from the 28th to the 29th, the XSF held its XMPP Summit in Brussels, Belgium. It was the 19th meeting by XMPP standards writers, implementers, and enthusiasts since the first XMPP Summit in July 2006.
Among the topics we discussed were MIX, efficient reconnections and, as always, end-to-end security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/XMPP2016?src=hash"&gt;#XMPP2016&lt;/a&gt; XSF at work at XMPP Summit &lt;a href="https://t.co/ZNEsilzJ2z"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ZNEsilzJ2z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Nicolas Vérité, Nÿco (@nyconyco) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nyconyco/status/692734779809251329"&gt;January 28, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MIX, defined in &lt;a href="//xmpp.org/extensions/xep-0369.html"&gt;XEP-0369: Mediated Information Exchange&lt;/a&gt;, is a replacement for the current multi-user chat standard (&lt;a href="//xmpp.org/extensions/xep-0045.html"&gt;XEP-0045&lt;/a&gt;). Classic MUC was first standardized 14 years ago. While it has received some updates and fixes over the years, it still has severe issues considering modern usage scenarios: like mobile devices without a permanent connection and on low bandwith, or rich-media applications with images, movies and voice/video conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIX is a new protocol aiming to solve these issues and provide a clean solution, based on &lt;a href="//xmpp.org/extensions/xep-0060.html"&gt;Publish-Subscribe&lt;/a&gt; allowing independent distribution of messages, configuration, presence and more, and &lt;a href="//xmpp.org/extensions/xep-0313.html"&gt;Message Archive Management&lt;/a&gt; for chat history. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIX related topics like mentioning others in a chat room, conversation threading and bookmarks have also been discussed and to some extent already standarized shortly after the summit. MIX will enable the implementation of modern group-chat applications with a good user experience in an easier fashion compared to classic MUC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple and efficient reconnection was another large topic discussed at the XMPP Summit. The protocol for a full connection of modern XMPP clients has become more complex and extensive over the years as features have been added. This includes stuff like TLS negotiation, synchronization of contact lists, feature discovery and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We collectively analyzed the protocol a modern feature-full XMPP client uses to login, and highlighted opportunities to reduce traffic, round trips and latency. An efficient reconnection is becoming more important as more and more chat applications run on a mobile device and reconnect quite often. A writeup of our findings and directions to possible optimizations will soon follow in the form of an informational XEP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, end-to-end security between XMPP clients was shortly discussed. The current ideas mainly evolve around &lt;a href="http://geekplace.eu/xeps/xep-openpgp/xep-openpgp.html"&gt;fixing OpenPGP usage in XMPP&lt;/a&gt; and the Axolotl-based &lt;a href="https://conversations.im/omemo/"&gt;OMEMO proposal&lt;/a&gt;. Here, our discussion mainly focused on current issues around the OMEMO proposal like missing support for full-stanza encryption and the threat model OMEMO is designed to protect against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the evening of the 28th, we also had our traditional XSF Dinner with interesting discussions and delicious food.
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Yummy meal. Honestly, best steak in Belgium at L&amp;#39;Auberge Bretonne for XSF dinner. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/XMPP2016?src=hash"&gt;#XMPP2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dave Cridland (@DwdDave) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DwdDave/status/692837510498504704"&gt;January 28, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/XMPP2016?src=hash"&gt;#XMPP2016&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/oWNO1LopMN"&gt;https://t.co/oWNO1LopMN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/fbYza3VO1C"&gt;pic.twitter.com/fbYza3VO1C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Sergey Dobrov (@JBinary) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JBinary/status/693001521382973440"&gt;January 29, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank the summit's sponsors, &lt;a href="http://www.ag-software.net/"&gt;AG-Software&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.cisco.com/"&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.surevine.com"&gt;Surevine&lt;/a&gt;, for enabling this great meetup and the XSF Dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;FOSDEM 2016&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href="https://fosdem.org/2016/schedule/track/real_time/"&gt;Real Time devroom&lt;/a&gt;, there has been a lot happening around the SIP and WebRTC protocols &amp;amp; ecosystems, but also around XMPP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panagiotis Stathopoulos presented &lt;a href="https://fosdem.org/2016/schedule/event/sharpxmpp/"&gt;"Sharp.Xmpp, a multiplatform .NET XMPP client library and Android"&lt;/a&gt; with some real world return of experience around battery and bandwidth efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicolas (Nÿco) Vérité presented &lt;a href="https://fosdem.org/2016/schedule/event/state_of_xmpp/"&gt;"The state of XMPP and instant messaging, The awakening"&lt;/a&gt; introducing the 3 generations of Instant Messaging, the trough of disillusionment, and consequently the necessary cleanup yet to be accomplished.
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;The state of XMPP and instant messaging at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FOSDEM2016?src=hash"&gt;#FOSDEM2016&lt;/a&gt; thx &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/michalwski"&gt;@michalwski&lt;/a&gt; for the pic &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/XMPP2016?src=hash"&gt;#XMPP2016&lt;/a&gt; it was fun, thx to all! &lt;a href="https://t.co/9CNqIYSwQz"&gt;pic.twitter.com/9CNqIYSwQz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Nicolas Vérité, Nÿco (@nyconyco) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nyconyco/status/693449757155577856"&gt;January 30, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave Cridland talked about &lt;a href="https://fosdem.org/2016/schedule/event/openfire/"&gt;"Reigniting Openfire: A tale of birth, death, zombies, and resurrection"&lt;/a&gt; (with a lie about zombies), showing the history of the &lt;a href="http://www.igniterealtime.org/projects/openfire/"&gt;Openfire&lt;/a&gt; XMPP server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew Wild talked about &lt;a href="https://fosdem.org/2016/schedule/event/xmpp_beyond_standards/"&gt;"XMPP: Beyond standards, Exploring the non-technical requirements of open communication"&lt;/a&gt; which echoes the need to focus less on lower layers, but more in the user space.
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Matthew Wild presenting &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/XMPP2016?src=hash"&gt;#XMPP2016&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/prosody?src=hash"&gt;#prosody&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FOSDEM?src=hash"&gt;#FOSDEM&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/YS8zxjI33t"&gt;pic.twitter.com/YS8zxjI33t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Steffen Larsen (@zooldk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/zooldk/status/693456193189232641"&gt;January 30, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jérôme Poisson (Goffi) presented &lt;a href="https://fosdem.org/2016/schedule/event/decentralized_blogging_with_xmpp/"&gt;"How we built a decentralized blogging engine with XMPP"&lt;/a&gt; in Libervia (Salut à Toi), demonstrating the capacities of XMPP outside of chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Real Time lounge was a booth where people could sit in large cushions, to openly discuss about Real Time Communications.
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Setting up at FOSDEM. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/XMPP2016?src=hash"&gt;#XMPP2016&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/Y0Yv9cxOBL"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Y0Yv9cxOBL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dave Cridland (@DwdDave) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DwdDave/status/693352392914530304"&gt;January 30, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Main Track, beyond the scope of only Real Time Communications, Daniel Pocock presented &lt;a href="https://fosdem.org/2016/schedule/event/free_communications/"&gt;"Free communications with Free Software is there any credible way to build a trustworthy communications platform without using free software?"&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Daniel Pocock introducing humourously &amp;quot;Free comms with free software&amp;quot; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FOSDEM2016?src=hash"&gt;#FOSDEM2016&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/xmpp2016?src=hash"&gt;#xmpp2016&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/uYzSL9VPiw"&gt;pic.twitter.com/uYzSL9VPiw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Nicolas Vérité, Nÿco (@nyconyco) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nyconyco/status/693721422523437056"&gt;January 31, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the participants were &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/michalwski/status/695155070246215681"&gt;all&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/winfriedtilanus/status/693890533442392064"&gt;quite&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/iNPUTmice/status/693822618735108096"&gt;satisfied&lt;/a&gt; with what they achieved and we are looking forward to our next XMPP Summit.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>XMPP at the end of the Google Summer of Code 2015</title><link href="/2015/12/xmpp-at-the-end-of-the-google-summer-of-code-2015" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-18T13:41:00+01:00</published><author><name>Kev</name></author><id>tag:,2015-12-18:2015/12/xmpp-at-the-end-of-the-google-summer-of-code-2015</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year we had six students working on disparate projects for GSoC, and we're delighted that all of them were successful! Here we link to a wrapup blog post from each of the students, and a description of their work from their mentors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had Adhish Singh working on &lt;a href="http://www.xmpp-iot.org/gsoc/week-12/"&gt;Internet of Things implementations&lt;/a&gt;. His mentor, Joachim, said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Adhish Singla: [Prototyping tools for IoT](http://www.xmpp-iot.org/gsoc/)

Adhish started from no XMPP experience and have created 2 graphical interfaces to IoT devices supporting xep 323 and xep 325 (experimental). One as a standalone Cordova mobile application and one as part of the converse.js webpage xmpp client. He also implemented a python history client that is instatiated as another resource on a Device IoT JID and polls the device for momentary values and stores history in db or local storage. So when clients ask for historical data it will in parallell with the originating device return the longtime history as part of the XEP323 history part. The javascript parts was done with crafted IQ messaging but will be enhanced with real plugin usage that is now part of the strophe package. python code will be submitted into SleekXMPP distribution. Converse code is running on the [site](http://www.xmpp-iot.org/).
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had Andreas Straub working on &lt;a href="http://conversationsgsoc2015.blogspot.co.uk/2015/09/omemo.html"&gt;end to end encryption in the Conversations client&lt;/a&gt;. His mentor Daniel says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Andreas Straub: Implementing Axolotl over XMPP
In just three month time Andreas managed to basically invent and implement a completely new protocol for multi-end to multi-end encryption. Compared to the commonly used OTR encryption which has  reliability problems in mobile- and multi client setups the new protocol works very well with multiple clients and offline messages while maintaining crypto features such as deniability and forward secrecy. Even after the Google Summer of Code was over Andreas stuck around and created an XEP based on the experienced gather during the implementation. It is currently in the inbox of the XSF and called 'OMEMO Encryption'. A new name was chosen to highlight the fact that - besides using axolotl internally - it is a completely new protocol and incompatible with other implementations that utilize axolotl.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had Daniel Baczynski working on &lt;a href="http://danielbgsoc.blogspot.co.uk/2015/08/polishing-and-fixing-existing-code.html"&gt;multi-account support in the Swift client&lt;/a&gt;. His mentor, Kev, says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Daniel had a tricky job this summer - to add support for using multiple accounts at once to the Swift client. Rather than being protocol-difficult, as some of the other projects, this one was tricky because of the pervasive nature of and difficult user experience changes needed in the project. Over the course of the summer he made significant progress towards multaccount support, and we hope to have the feature completed for a future release.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had Ishan Khanna working on serverless messaging in the Smack library. His mentor Florian says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Ishan Khanna, Add support for XMPP Serverless Messaging (XEP-174) to Smack

From the very start Ishan was very motivated to add support for
serverless messaging based on DNS-SD and mDNS as described in XEP-147 to
Smack. While the problem description is trivial, the solution involves
many protocols (XMPP, DNS-SD, mDNS, ...), concepts and technology stacks
(Smack, jmdns, ...) that need to be understood in order to be able to
implement XMPP serverless messaging. Ishan implemented a working
solution and and demonstrated how other XMPP clients are able to
discover and exchange messages with the smack serverless implementation.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had Marvin Wißfeld working on &lt;a href="http://mar-v-in.github.io/gsoc15/weekly-report/2015/08/21/thanks.html"&gt;DNSSEC support in the Smack library&lt;/a&gt;. His mentor Dave says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Marvin W: Adding DNSSEC Support to Smack via miniDNS

A solid implementation of DNSSEC that can span everything from server to mobile would be an accomplishment from any developer - to get this done from scratch in a single summer as a student in GSoC really is amazingly impressive. XMPP relies on DNS for federated service discovery, both from client to server and between servers, and including DNSSEC in this capability gives a huge uplift in security across the board, providing cryptographically assured DNS lookups. Marvin implemented this in miniDNS, and added the needed support to Smack, so this can now be available on Android and desktop clients, and miniDNS can be used by servers as well.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had Tarun Gupta working on &lt;a href="http://tarun018.blogspot.co.uk/2015/08/wrap-up.html"&gt;extending the Stroke library with all the features from its Swiften sister-project&lt;/a&gt;. His mentor Kev said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Tarun took on a huge project this summer and achieved much more than I would have expected. His project to update Stroke with all the features available in the Swiften library was a great success, and has made Stroke much more useful for developers. Over the course of the summer Tarun touched nearly 600 files, and ported over 35,000 lines of code. A massive achievement.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all the students for their efforts over the summer, and good luck in their future endeavours (although we hope they'll stick around!).&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Seeking new XSF Treasurer</title><link href="/2015/07/seeking-new-xsf-treasurer" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-06T11:05:00+02:00</published><author><name>Simon</name></author><id>tag:,2015-07-06:2015/07/seeking-new-xsf-treasurer</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Until now, St Peter has been handling the XSF Treasurer role. He's stepping down from the role and the XSF Board is looking for someone new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The role of Treasurer includes overall responsibility for the financial affairs of the XSF. The future treasurer would:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain and monitor the XSF's bank account with Wells Fargo NA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain and monitor the XSF's post office box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File income tax reports (Form 990) with the US IRS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay franchise taxes with the State of Delaware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay corporate registration fees with NRAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay for relevant domain name registrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send invoices to XSF sponsors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reimburse XSF members for approved out-of-pockets costs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report on XSF finances to the Board of Directors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we're looking for someone new. If you or someone you know would be interested in serving as the treasurer (they don't necessarily even have to be an XSF member), please get in touch with the board or me directly. It would be great to have this post filled!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested, please get in touch with a member of the &lt;a href="http://xmpp.org/about-xmpp/xsf/the-xsf-board-of-directors/"&gt;XSF Board&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Eyeball Networks become an XSF Sponsor</title><link href="/2015/05/eyeball-networks-become-an-xsf-sponsor" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-26T08:29:00+02:00</published><author><name>willsheward</name></author><id>tag:,2015-05-26:2015/05/eyeball-networks-become-an-xsf-sponsor</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We're happy to announce that Eyeball Networks are the latest organisation to become an XSF Sponsor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eyeball Networks pioneered the STUN/TURN/ICE device-to-device connection technologies adopted by communications standards including SIP, XMPP, IMS, PacketCable, IBM Sametime, Microsoft Lync, and now WebRTC. You can read more about them &lt;a href="http://xmpp.org/sponsor/our-sponsors/eyeball-networks/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsors are vital to the ability of the XSF to continue to fulfil its &lt;a href="http://xmpp.org/about-xmpp/xsf/xsf-mission/"&gt;mission&lt;/a&gt; to build an open, secure, feature-rich, decentralized infrastructure for real-time communication and collaboration over the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our sponsors help us with everything from infrastructure for the XMPP site to funding the regular XMPP Summits so please take the time to thanks Eyeball Networks by visiting their website, getting them involved in discussions and perhaps following them on your social network of choice (from &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/eyeball-networks" title="LinkedIn"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/EyeballNetworks" title="Facebook: Eyeball Networks"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/eyeballnetworks" title="Twitter: Eyeball Networks"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/+EyeballNetworks/posts" title="Google+: Eyeball Networks"&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;).
 &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>XSF GSoC Students 2015</title><link href="/2015/04/xsf-gsoc-students-2015" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-28T09:43:00+02:00</published><author><name>kev</name></author><id>tag:,2015-04-28:2015/04/xsf-gsoc-students-2015</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year, we've been lucky enough to have had many great applications to take part in Google Summer of Code under the XSF. We've selected the following six students/projects and are looking forward to working with them over an exciting summer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tarun Gupta&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/project/details/google/gsoc2015/tarun018/5741031244955648"&gt;Extend Stroke Implementation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Daniel Baczynski&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/project/details/google/gsoc2015/matrix4/5724160613416960"&gt;Multi-account support in Swift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ishan Khanna&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/project/details/google/gsoc2015/ishan1604/5697982787747840"&gt;Add support for XMPP Serverless Messaging (XEP-174) to Smack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marvin W&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/project/details/google/gsoc2015/larma/5643440998055936"&gt;Add support for DNSSEC to Smack via MiniDNS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;srtb&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/project/details/google/gsoc2015/strb/5750085036015616"&gt;Axolotl support for Conversations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adhish Singla&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/project/details/google/gsoc2015/adhish/5724160613416960"&gt;Prototyping tools, for Internet of Things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should be a great summer for the students, and for all the projects involved.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Board goals for 2015</title><link href="/2015/03/board-goals-for-2015" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-03-23T04:51:00+01:00</published><author><name>laura</name></author><id>tag:,2015-03-23:2015/03/board-goals-for-2015</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When our newest Board of Directors were elected, they decided that they wanted to set some goals against which their achievements as Board members could be measured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so this journey began...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started by asking the community what THEY cared about and what they wanted the Board to focus on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took this information, turned it into measurable objectives and then asked the community to vote - what did they think the most important areas to focus on? There was a lot of debate here, and we listened - the measurables could have been something else, there are other ways of looking at this etc - but, we had to commit to something or a year on we would still be working how to measure what we were doing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is what got decided (the meeting minutes can be found &lt;a href="http://logs.xmpp.org/xsf/2015-02-23/#16:03:11"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;% based goals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="percentage copy.jpg" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/bAGEeNO4Ty2AWOAA9vbe53hJKpbNQ7xtMy20bvEOXcc3ne9nlEbkpwrJmIa2Zxm90t3IJJlyVGpZnAI61AXqb2YrceZJLVffLkyenDZoyhTB9oFDcmLGq9DkIh9rM_dxuiBQEj4" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recognised that there were two top scorers - website traffic and membership engagement. While membership engagement is of obvious importance, the Board felt that engagement would be covered by other activities and was possibly too inwardly focussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decision: Website traffic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Binary goals&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="binary copy.jpg" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/9Tbj_LL-gX6qHZbjKEZ2KRq4Efhc7RbqF8nU8_qe-3YfBOspzuG3XwgTGNg8dCEZ62BfITT7K5FH5HIpBmiLzK0_FXPYWw23XSwzUJX7YzgHsRi1gdRVp7P6g6_q94v78ijzfi8" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our binary goal, there was a clear leader, although a difficult goal! How we achieve this goal needs more discussion, but the decision was unanimous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decision: IOT strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soft goals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="soft copy.jpg" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_1-LZyOHKdYXViIUm09mheicBcV4phDmtoLyTmev45601YClU2UC-KyEnT4Hi9qH_GC_ermo80vdZYx9LjBI4qCuNxOaIleYU06jx9D6zfAtukAKaEXlJ6XujK_nvxpdcs8yCco" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the ‘Benefits of federation’ was clearly the highest rated objective for our “soft goal”, the Board recognised that this was simply an aspect of XMPP positioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decision: XMPP positioning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is where we are at. The % based goal and XMPP positioning are both being worked on at the moment, through the development of our new website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will keep you posted with our progress...&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Summit 17 - the presentations</title><link href="/2015/03/summit-17-the-presentations" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-03-20T05:23:00+01:00</published><author><name>laura</name></author><id>tag:,2015-03-20:2015/03/summit-17-the-presentations</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A slightly tardy share, but we have the presentations from Summit 17 in Brussels starting to trickle in! As more come in, this post will get longer (and hopefully have a more permanent home on the new site) but here we go:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XMPP Research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With their active blog &lt;a href="http://xmppresearch.org/"&gt;xmppresearch.org&lt;/a&gt;, researchers from RWTH Aachen University and TU Dresden are contributing to an ongoing collection of academic works around XMPP, including a high-quality bibliography, demos and reviews. Domink Renzel presented their work and their goals to the Summit members.
-   &lt;a href="http://xmpp.org/files/xmpp_research_org.pdf"&gt;A blog on XMPP Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blogging via XMPP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sergey Dobrov walked us through federated blogging and a combination of XMPP &amp;amp; PubSub/PEP. The presentation includes a call-out for help, and hwo you can get involved.
-   &lt;a href="http://jbinary.github.io/xmpp-blogging-presentation/"&gt;Presentation in github&lt;/a&gt;
-   &lt;a href="http://xmpp.org/files/xmpp_blogging.pdf"&gt;Presentation on this site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would love to showcase more of the presentations, so if you have anything from the Summit you would like to share, please get in touch!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>An introduction to xmppresearch.org</title><link href="/2015/03/an-introduction-to-xmppresearchorg" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-03-03T08:15:00+01:00</published><author><name>willsheward</name></author><id>tag:,2015-03-03:2015/03/an-introduction-to-xmppresearchorg</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the recent Summit 17, we were very happy to welcome Dominik Renzel and István Koren from the recently launched site &lt;a href="http://www.xmppresearch.org/"&gt;xmppresearch.org&lt;/a&gt;. The declared mission of the project is to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;collect and to present scientific research work based on XMPP&amp;quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The site, which is a collaboration between RWTH Aachen University and Technische Universität Dresden, contains articles on recent XMPP-related research, demos and a comprehensive bibliography. They've recently blogged about &lt;a href="http://www.xmppresearch.org/posts/xmppresearch-org-at-xmpp-summit-17/"&gt;their experiences at Summit 17&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're looking at ways of more formally linking this excellent site to the XSF's own online efforts. In the meantime I’m sure they would welcome you contacting them with any relevant XMPP research you are aware of so it can be included on their site.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>XMPP in Google Summer of Code 2015</title><link href="/2015/03/xmpp-in-google-summer-of-code-2015" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-03-03T06:20:00+01:00</published><author><name>kev</name></author><id>tag:,2015-03-03:2015/03/xmpp-in-google-summer-of-code-2015</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've just had the great news that Google have again accepted the XSF to mentor XMPP-related projects in the Google Summer of Code this year. GSoC is a programme whereby Google pays students a stipend to work on open source projects for the summer, and when we're able to participate in this it's a highlight of the year for us. If you are, or know any, talented students with an interest in realtime communication systems we've got a selection of interesting projects at &lt;a href="http://wiki.xmpp.org/web/Summer_of_Code_2015"&gt;http://wiki.xmpp.org/web/Summer_of_Code_2015&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our page on the GSoC site is at &lt;a href="https://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/org2/google/gsoc2015/xmpp"&gt;https://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/org2/google/gsoc2015/xmpp&lt;/a&gt;, and for more information on GSoC in general please see the Google site at &lt;a href="https://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/homepage/google/gsoc2015"&gt;https://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/homepage/google/gsoc2015&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student applications open on March 16th but that's no reason to delay - come and chat with us about our possible projects with the contact venues listed on &lt;a href="http://wiki.xmpp.org/web/Summer_of_Code_2015"&gt;http://wiki.xmpp.org/web/Summer_of_Code_2015&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've got the ideas, we've got the mentors, all we need are a few students to turn this into a great summer for XMPP.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>No, it's not the end of XMPP for Google Talk</title><link href="/2015/03/no-its-not-the-end-of-xmpp-for-google-talk" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-03-02T12:40:00+01:00</published><author><name>fippo</name></author><id>tag:,2015-03-02:2015/03/no-its-not-the-end-of-xmpp-for-google-talk</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There's some recent discussion about the sky falling for XMPP at Google. See &lt;a href="http://www.disruptivetelephony.com/2015/02/google-finally-kills-off-googletalk-and-xmpp-jabber-integration.html"&gt;this blog post by Dan York&lt;/a&gt; for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, we don't know the state of XMPP inside Google because they don't share their use of XMPP with the XSF. We do know Android's &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/google/gcm/ccs.html"&gt;Google Cloud Messaging&lt;/a&gt; uses it. We know &lt;a href="http://juberti.blogspot.com/2011/07/hangouts-mailbag.html"&gt;Hangouts Videochat uses it&lt;/a&gt;. We know Google Talk still (insecurely) federates with (some) XMPP services. But from an outside perspective, Google has made no major recent changes in terms of how they're using XMPP from what we can observe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what happened?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Google Talk app for Windows has been deprecated as of February 23, 2015 &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/+MayurKamat/posts/ETBvtp9VYav"&gt;as explained by the product manager&lt;/a&gt;. Google &lt;a href="http://googleappsupdates.blogspot.ca/2014/10/notification-re-google-talk-app-for.html"&gt;announced a while ago&lt;/a&gt; they intended to do this, but it comes as little surprise given the client has not seen much development in this decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of Google Talk, Hangouts is promoted. Hangouts does not interoperate with federated XMPP clients. Users appear as visible, but messages from federated contacts are lost, which is a very confusing user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The XSF still believes in the principle of client choice, best explained by Google on their &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/talk/open_communications"&gt;developer pages&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe users should have choice in which clients they use to &amp;gt; connect to the Google Talk service and we want to encourage the &amp;gt; developer community to create new and innovative applications that &amp;gt; leverage our service. To enable this, Google Talk uses the standard &amp;gt; XMPP protocol for authentication, presence, and messaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that you can still continue to use the Google Talk Service with a third party XMPP client and the Google Talk XMPP servers continue to federate with other domains.   This is called "service choice". The principle is, again, &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/talk/open_communications#service_1"&gt;best explained by Google&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Service choice is something you have with email and, for the most &amp;gt; part, with your regular phone service today. This means that &amp;gt; regardless of whom you choose as your email service provider (Gmail, &amp;gt; Hotmail, Yahoo! Mail, your school or ISP, etc), you can email anyone &amp;gt; who is using another service provider. The same applies to phone &amp;gt; service. You can call someone even if they do not use the same phone &amp;gt; company as you do. This allows you to choose your service provider &amp;gt; based on other more important factors, such as features, quality of &amp;gt; service, and price, while still being able to talk to anyone you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, since the Google Talk Service does not support server-to-server encryption via TLS (something that was required by RFC 3920 in 2004), a number of servers (including jabber.org) refuse to establish a connection &lt;a href="http://xmpp.org/2014/05/happy-encrypted-network/"&gt;since May 2014&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd love to see Google embrace secure messaging for federated messaging. But aside from this long-standing issue, XMPP is alive and kicking at Google.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Thank you to new and returning XSF sponsors</title><link href="/2015/02/thank-you-to-new-and-returning-xsf-sponsors" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-02-16T11:41:00+01:00</published><author><name>willsheward</name></author><id>tag:,2015-02-16:2015/02/thank-you-to-new-and-returning-xsf-sponsors</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We'd like to say a big "thank you" to two companies who have recently signed up as sponsors of the XMPP Standards Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://xmpp.org/sponsor/our-sponsors/erlang-solutions/"&gt;Erlang Solutions&lt;/a&gt; are a new XSF sponsor who specialise in providing businesses with scalable solutions via the creation, integration, delivery and lifetime support of products and services based on the Erlang and Elixir programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://xmpp.org/sponsor/our-sponsors/processone/"&gt;ProcessOne, a returning sponsor&lt;/a&gt;, are a leading provider in messaging platforms designed for scale and robustness. ProcessOne have developed ejabberd, an ubiquitous XMPP server that has been deployed to power some of the largest messaging platform in the world. Many people will remember their CEO, Mickaël Rémond, as a member of the Board of the XSF for a number of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were all very happy to see representatives from both Erlang Solutions and ProcessOne at the recent Summit 17 where they contributed greatly to discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again to both of these great companies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in sponsoring the XSF, you can find more details on &lt;a href="http://xmpp.org/sponsor/sponsor-the-xsf/"&gt;our sponsorship page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>It’s all about choices and control</title><link href="/2015/01/its-all-about-choices-and-control" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-01-26T07:59:00+01:00</published><author><name>laura</name></author><id>tag:,2015-01-26:2015/01/its-all-about-choices-and-control</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;"Why should I use XMPP?” is a question we get asked a lot. Our answer is often technically-focussed, as there are plenty of reasons XMPP might be the right choice, or we might explain about the benefits of a federated approach - where everyone can run their own server and control their own data. Either way, the fact it is an ‘open standard’ never ceases to be mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open standards have many advantages over proprietary formats (too many to list in one blog post) but one in particular is that it gives you the choices and control about how you access your data and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example (get ready for the analogies) imagine you are an individual accessing someone else’s XMPP service. Because XMPP is built on open standards, you get to choose what applications you use to connect to their system; for example, a mobile phone provider does not mandate that to use their services you must use a specific handset - the choice is yours). Your provider may have one that they prefer, or offer, but there are myriad other XMPP applications - the choice remains yours and you can make that choice based on your individual preferences and requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even better, if a new project implements a better XMPP client than the one you are currently using, firstly, that project is able to do so, and secondly - you are free to start using it! Back to our phone analogy, imagine if a new mobile handset came out that was even better than the one you had chosen, and you could just pop your sim card out of the old phone and straight into the new one… no hassle, but a much better service for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you have particular needs not being met by existing clients, you are freely able to implement your own or to extend any of the open source options to meet those requirements. The power is all yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a critically important difference between open standards (like XMPP) and access to proprietary systems - if you use a proprietary system, the operator is in control of how you access the service; and on a whim they could choose to shut down your choice of third-party clients. Using our phone analogy, this is like your mobile service provider controlling which handsets you can use, and on a whim deciding that they have 1 choice and only than handset can be used from now on. In this situation you might find yourself unable to access your data in a useful way. A proprietary system may also release a new version of the client that you don’t like or that doesn’t run on your systems; if they force upgrades you may no longer be able to access the systems or your data. As you can see, the choice isn’t really yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, imagine you are an organisation running an internal service. You might choose to use a cloud provider, in which case the advantages of choosing a vendor using open standards is the same as above. You might also want to apply organisational policies to your internal service; here again, open standards like XMPP are a good choice. They ensure that you can choose the client you need, not the client the vendor of a proprietary system wants you to use. An open-standards system even ensures (with the ability to export your data) the option to migrate from one server provider to another using mechanisms defined for XMPP servers. When its your systems, it should be your choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These advantages also apply to third-party developers - developing for XMPP gives you a level playing field and you’re free to implement your client, server, library, or component according to the standards; you don’t run the risk of being locked out of the systems for which you’re developing, either by unpublished protocol changes or by legal action. And if you think the protocols can be better, you can even contribute to the open standards process and make improvements you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using open standards matters whenever your choices are important to you, be it today or tomorrow. And that is why you should use XMPP.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>XMPP Summit 17</title><link href="/2015/01/xmpp-summit-17" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-01-08T04:25:00+01:00</published><author><name>joachim.lindborg</name></author><id>tag:,2015-01-08:2015/01/xmpp-summit-17</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The 17th XSF Summit is approaching!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 29th and 30th 2015, just before &lt;a href="http://wiki.xmpp.org/web/FOSDEM_2015"&gt;FOSDEM2015&lt;/a&gt;. members of the XMPP community will be gathering at the Cisco offices in Diegem, Brussels to talk about all things XMPP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our agenda is evolving but so far includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://xmpp-iot.org"&gt;XMPP-IoT&lt;/a&gt;, Current state of the IoT XEPs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editor team automation sprint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e2e encryption &amp;amp; OTR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The state of UPNP and their XMPP cloud project (and us as liaisons)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relation/Liaison to W3C interest group on the Web of Things: &lt;a href="http://www.w3.org/2014/12/wot-ig-charter.html"&gt;charter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XEP-0322 EXI: Update on/upstreaming of implementation, comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep up to date with Summit plans, please visit the &lt;a href="http://wiki.xmpp.org/web/Summit_17"&gt;wiki page for Summit 17&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you intend to come along to the Summit, please join the &lt;a href="http://mail.jabber.org/mailman/listinfo/summit"&gt;summit@xmpp.org discussion list&lt;/a&gt; and post with your participation request.
 &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Upcoming events</title><link href="/2014/05/upcoming-events" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-30T03:23:00+02:00</published><author><name>laura</name></author><id>tag:,2014-05-30:2014/05/upcoming-events</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Until our new website launches with a dedicated 'whats on' section, I wanted to share some events coming up that might be of interest to our community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rikardstrid"&gt;Rikard Strid&lt;/a&gt;of Clayster is speaking at 2 events in June, focussing in on XMPP and IoT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fo those of you over in America (or for those that now have an excuse to head that way!) here are the details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12 June: &lt;a href="http://iot.ulitzer.com/node/3015783"&gt;IOT Expo&lt;/a&gt; in NYC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16 June: &lt;a href="http://iotworldevent.com/open-source-iot/"&gt;IOT World&lt;/a&gt; in Silicon Valley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully we can get a blog post from Rikard after the events, to share the goodness with everyone that couldn't attend.
 &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Happy Encrypted Network!</title><link href="/2014/05/happy-encrypted-network" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-19T12:16:00+02:00</published><author><name>stpeter</name></author><id>tag:,2014-05-19:2014/05/happy-encrypted-network</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, a large number of services on the public XMPP network permanently turned on mandatory encryption for client-to-server and server-to-server connections (there's a fine summary &lt;a href="http://blog.prosody.im/mandatory-encryption-on-xmpp-starts-today/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first step toward making the XMPP network more secure for all users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more updates as we work on ubiquitous authentication, secure DNS, end-to-end encryption, and other improvements.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>XMPP on the Global Internet of Things Day</title><link href="/2014/04/xmpp-on-the-global-internet-of-things-day" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-04-07T17:10:00+02:00</published><author><name>joachim.lindborg</name></author><id>tag:,2014-04-07:2014/04/xmpp-on-the-global-internet-of-things-day</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The 9th of april is the Global IoT day  (&lt;em&gt;Internet of Things day&lt;/em&gt;)  on the site  &lt;a href="http://iotday.org/"&gt;iotday.org&lt;/a&gt; and on &lt;a href="http://iotlive.org"&gt;iotlive.org&lt;/a&gt; events and meetups around the world are celebrating and connecting live devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#IoTDayStockholm is coordinating several schedules from events in different time zones and will be having workshops creating XMPP IoT enabled devices. These will be open to interact with, to read and write values over the secure XMPP network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0Alq4m6luZ2DZdGVYOHI1RVVKWE5mQTB6anFFcVBxX3c&amp;amp;usp=sharing"&gt;look here for the  schedule&lt;/a&gt; here and many details on &lt;a href="http://iea-sust.se/category/iotday"&gt;http://iea-sust.se/category/iotday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://iea.sust.se/2014/04/04/global-iot-day-stockholm-all-details/"&gt;Register to the open webinar if you cannot be there in person&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sensei-iot.org/PDF/IoTDay2014_Washington_DC.pdf"&gt;IEEE/ISO/IEC is holding a virtual conference from washington DC that you canjoin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/The-San-Francisco-Internet-of-Things-Meetup/events/169305542/"&gt;The XMPP sponsor Coversant is also participating in the San Fransisco meetup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Security Notice: Uncontrolled Resource Consumption with Highly-Compressed XMPP Stanzas</title><link href="/2014/04/security-notice-uncontrolled-resource-consumption-with-highly-compressed-xmpp-stanzas" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-04-04T09:24:00+02:00</published><author><name>stpeter</name></author><id>tag:,2014-04-04:2014/04/security-notice-uncontrolled-resource-consumption-with-highly-compressed-xmpp-stanzas</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The XMPP Standards Foundation has published a security notice describing an uncontrolled resource consumption vulnerability in several XMPP server implementations that support application-layer compression. Details can be found at &lt;a href="http://xmpp.org/resources/security-notices/uncontrolled-resource-consumption-with-highly-compressed-xmpp-stanzas/"&gt;http://xmpp.org/resources/security-notices/uncontrolled-resource-consumption-with-highly-compressed-xmpp-stanzas/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Third Security Test Day</title><link href="/2014/03/third-security-test-day" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-03-21T11:56:00+01:00</published><author><name>stpeter</name></author><id>tag:,2014-03-21:2014/03/third-security-test-day</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow sees the third security test day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security test days help XMPP operators test-run with strong encryption settings prior to the big encryption switch-over scheduled for 19 May 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large number of XMPP sites have already signed up to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/stpeter/manifesto"&gt;ubiquitous encryption manifesto&lt;/a&gt;. More so, some of the participating sites have already permanently enabled strong encryption prior to the manifesto's go-live date!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the sites is Crypho. CTO Dr. Yiorgis Gozadinos explained his thinking in enabling strong encryption: “Everybody should have the right to privacy and confidentiality. Providing sane, strong encryption standards built-in in XMPP is a huge step to that direction."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ludost.net site admin Vasil Kolev has also been protecting his user's privacy: "Without strong encryption, these services become worse than useless - they become dangerous for the people that use them."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jabber.org, the original XMPP server on the Internet, is another site that has been playing an active role in the test days. As primary operator Peter Saint-Andre noted, "Although we've had the ability to encrypt the XMPP network for many years now, it's great to see strong momentum toward achieving that goal in the near future."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To join the growing number of sites that are enabling strong encryption:
​
1. Sign the &lt;a href="https://github.com/stpeter/manifesto"&gt;manifesto&lt;/a&gt; as an XMPP server admin or software developer. &lt;br /&gt;
2. Setup your site's encryption and check it at &lt;a href="https://xmpp.net/"&gt;XMPP.net&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
3. Run with TLS encryption required on the 22nd of March and report issues in the &lt;a href="xmpp:operators@muc.xmpp.org?join"&gt;operators chatroom&lt;/a&gt; or on the &lt;a href="http://mail.jabber.org/mailman/listinfo/operators"&gt;operators discussion list&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
4. Spread the word about building secure federated communication!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Google Summer of Code 2014</title><link href="/2014/02/google-summer-of-code-2014" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-02-28T12:25:00+01:00</published><author><name>laura</name></author><id>tag:,2014-02-28:2014/02/google-summer-of-code-2014</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;While the XSF may not be mentoring a project in this years &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/soc/"&gt;Google's Summer of Code 2014&lt;/a&gt; -  we sure can celebrate and shout about the fact that some of the projects include XMPP as part of their project ideas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://jitsi.org/Development/GSoC"&gt;Jitsi&lt;/a&gt; project has several projects relating to WebRTC, XMPP and the Jitsi Videobridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XMPP/Jingle/WebRTC also plays a role in Mozilla's project ideas for &lt;a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/Community:SummerOfCode14#Instantbird"&gt;InstantBird&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To name just a few...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are really looking forward to seeing many of these exciting projects get implemented by students around the world!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Second Security Test Day</title><link href="/2014/02/second-security-test-day" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-02-18T11:56:00+01:00</published><author><name>stpeter</name></author><id>tag:,2014-02-18:2014/02/second-security-test-day</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This Saturday (February 22, 2014), XMPP site operators are again flipping the "encrypt all traffic" switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second of four test days kicked off by the &lt;a href="https://github.com/stpeter/manifesto/blob/master/manifesto.txt"&gt;manifesto&lt;/a&gt; first published last fall. The aim is to encrypt all traffic between servers and clients on the public, federated XMPP network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can take part, too: ensure you have valid certificates on your server and that encryption is properly set up (see &lt;a href="http://wiki.xmpp.org/web/Securing_XMPP"&gt;http://wiki.xmpp.org/web/Securing_XMPP&lt;/a&gt; along with the documentation for your XMPP server software), then test your configuration using the tools at the &lt;a href="https://xmpp.net/"&gt;IM Observatory&lt;/a&gt; running at XMPP.net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The manifesto team has managed to push the encryption level up to 12.5% of XMPP server-to-server traffic (see &lt;a href="https://xmpp.net/reports.php#starttls"&gt;https://xmpp.net/reports.php#starttls&lt;/a&gt;). The test days help to keep nudging this value up and to prepare for an "everything is encrypted...or else" day in May of this year (some operators have not flipped back to unencrypted traffic and are now running 100% encrypted servers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To join the team running the manifesto and thus help to secure the communications of XMPP users everywhere:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;test your server at the &lt;a href="https://xmpp.net/"&gt;IM Observatory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sign the manifesto at &lt;a href="https://github.com/stpeter/manifesto"&gt;https://github.com/stpeter/manifesto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chat with other XMPP operators in the &lt;a href="xmpp:operators@muc.xmpp.org?join"&gt;operators@muc.xmpp.org chatroom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;join the conversation on the &lt;a href="http://mail.jabber.org/mailman/listinfo/operators"&gt;operators@xmpp.org email list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's that easy!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>